ChargePoint global privacy policy
=================================

Last updated: December 17th, 2024
---------------------------------

ChargePoint (“ChargePoint,” “we,” “our” or “us”) — defined as any entity directly or indirectly controlled by ChargePoint Inc., 240 East Hacienda Ave., Campbell, CA 95008 USA — provides this privacy policy (the “Policy”) to inform you on how we process your information, whether you are a visitor to our website, a user of the ChargePoint app, an operator of our electric vehicle (EV) charging stations, a user of EV charging stations on the ChargePoint network, a user of a ChargePoint account, an owner of a ChargePoint radio-frequency identification (RFID) card, a user of our EV monitoring solutions, a user of any other service offered by ChargePoint that includes a link to this Policy, or a visitor of our offices in Europe. Each of these services and applications are collectively defined as the “Service(s)”.

The “ChargePoint network” is defined as the network of electric vehicle charging stations and the vehicle charging and telematics applications that the network delivers, which is operated and maintained by ChargePoint. Please read this Policy carefully to understand our practices regarding your personal data and how we collect, process and transfer it. By using or otherwise accessing the Service, you acknowledge the applicability of this Policy. If you have any questions about this Policy or how we handle your personal data, please contact us as described below in Section 11.

1. **Information we collect**  

    We obtain information about you when you use or otherwise access the Services. Please note that we need certain types of information to provide the Services to you. If you do not provide us with such information or if you ask us to delete that information, you may no longer be able to access or use certain parts of our Services.
    
    1. Information you provide directly to us
        
        We collect information you provide directly to us. For example, you may provide us with information through:
        
        * Use of the Services
        * Registration for a user or administration account
        * Access to and use of the ChargePoint network
        * Purchases
        * Communications with us, including for customer support, technical assistance, marketing and billing
        * Communications with other users of the Service
        * Participation in surveys, polls, sweepstakes or promotions
        
        The types of information we collect directly from you may include:
        
        * **Account registration data.** If you register for an account, we may collect your full name, username, password, title, email address, telephone number, postal code, address, device information, IP addresses and other log files, as well as how you interacted with the Service. In addition, we may collect your RFID card number, user identification, user differentiator, contract information including conditions and fees, or payment information including invoices and turnovers (document date and number, last four digits of your credit card number, total amount and currency, line items, payment status, date of document dispatch, tax and recipient information, etc.). You may also provide other information to us through your account, such as driver tips, station images, photos uploaded, your full address or information about your vehicle (e.g., make, model, color, etc.).
        * **Charging network data.** When you use the ChargePoint network, we may collect information about your charging session such as charging station location, charging station name, charging session date, start time, end time, duration, performance curve, energy dispensed, charging port identification number, parking time, authorization details including identification media, total fees associated with each charging session, payment method, pricing policy applied, (RFID card) identification number, or power cycle patterns, current and voltage.
        * **ChargePoint station data.** If you own or operate a ChargePoint station for commercial use, we collect certain information from you as a “Site Host,” such as contact details and your Site Host affiliation or association to a company account. If you own or operate a ChargePoint station for home use, we may collect your name, phone number, email address, physical address, session and scheduling data, and the Wi-Fi network name you use connect to the ChargePoint station.
        * **Customer support data.** If you call our customer support line, we may record your conversations and collect case-related details.
        * **Communication data.** If you sign up for the Service, use the Service, or send an email or other communication to ChargePoint (e.g., phone call, text, push notification, etc.), we may retain your contact information and related communication.
        * **Survey data.** We may process information you provide through online surveys and polls.
        * **Business relationship data.** We may process information you provide in the context of a business relationship with ChargePoint in the capacity of a (potential) customer, vendor or partner. This information may include your name, company name, contact details such as phone number and email address, or notes and correspondence related to the transaction.
        * **Social media data.** When you use ChargePoint social media features we may collect your username and other information such as charging station name and charging station location.
        * **Telematics data.** If your company uses our telematics monitoring solutions and you are a driver of a connected vehicle, we collect account data (email address, name, username/driver ID, company name and team identifier) as well as data on driving behavior including vehicle identifier (VID), acceleration, speed, odometer (distance driven), voltage, current, fuel used, fuel level, gyroscope (orientation), pedal position, HVAC parameters, GPS location, trip information, operator name, time of departure, time of arrival, VIN (or other vehicle identifier), driver ID, route ID, route name, and route destination or direction. In addition, we collect service usage information (device information, location and log files) as well as data on how you used our dashboard.
        * **Camera footage.** In our offices, labs and warehouses, where we indicate this with a sign, we have cameras directed toward the entrance of the building, emergency exits, warehouse loading areas and high-voltage/low-voltage labs collecting video footage. Please note that the cameras do not record audio.
    2. Information we collect from third parties
        * **Connection data.** You may provide your name, login credentials (e.g., username and password, secret question and answer), contact information (e.g., email address, phone number, mailing address), vehicle information (optional) or optional information through the “Connections” feature as may be required by a charging station provider (“Provider”) such as a Site Host, your employer or leasing company. The Connections feature allows drivers to receive certain benefits (e.g., access, reimbursement, preferential pricing, etc.). A Provider may ask drivers for additional information to verify their identity to access the benefits. ChargePoint does not monitor or control the additional personal information requested by the Provider.
        * **Fraud and safety protection data.** We may also collect information about you from nonaffiliated third parties for fraud or safety protection purposes. We likewise may combine information that we collect from you through our Services with information that we obtain from such third parties and information derived from any other products or services we provide.
    3. Information we collect automatically
        * **App and website data.** When you use our app or visit our website, we and our third-party service providers may use cookies, web beacons and other tracking technologies to collect and store information about your use of the Service. As described further below, we may collect and analyze information including, but not limited to, IP address, device identifier, online identifiers, date and day of access request, pages viewed, time zone difference to Greenwich Mean Time (GMT), the standard HTTP header information, the time spent on each page of our website or app page, personal app information (first start, app opening, app update, in-app purchases, information on crash behavior of the app, RFC-4122 UUID, crash information, bundle ID, device identifier, additional app information), links you have clicked on our website, the page you visit before and after you come to our website, browser type, operating system, language, advertising identification number and vendor identifier, usage data including information on how you navigate the Services, and version of browser software.
        * **Location data.** When you use our Services, we may collect information from which your location could be derived (such as IP address). If you install our app, we may ask you to grant us access to your mobile device’s geolocation data. If you grant such permission, we may collect information about your precise geolocation, in order to provide you with location-based features such as identification of ChargePoint stations available near you. If you access the Service through a mobile device and you do not want your device to provide us with location-tracking information, you can disable the GPS or other location-tracking functions on your device or disable GPS only for the ChargePoint application, provided your device allows you to do this. See your device manufacturer's instructions for further details. If you disable certain functions, you may be unable to use certain aspects of our services.
        * **Customer support data.** When you call our customer support center, we may record the details of the communication as well as a general sense of the overall sentiment during the call, and we may generate a corresponding transcript of the conversation.
2. **Cookies and other electronic technologies**  

    ChargePoint uses cookies and similar technologies including web beacons, embedded scripts and e-tags (together referred to as “cookies,” unless otherwise stated) to provide users an efficient user experience in using the website. A cookie is a small data file that is placed on your computer or mobile device by your web browser. It is a tool that stores information about website visits, recognizes you and your preferences each time you visit the website, optimizes website functionality, and enables us to provide our Service.
    
    ChargePoint uses cookies for a variety of reasons, including to provide you the Service you have requested, enhance our website’s performance or analyze how people use our website.
    
    The table below explains the categories of cookies that are used on our website. Depending on your location and corresponding jurisdiction, we request that visitors provide permission (opt-in) prior to ChargePoint using such technologies. Alternatively, we provide granular controls through our Consent Management Platform, which enables visitors to keep only their preferred cookie categories. The following table summarizes our cookie categories.
    
    | Cookie type | Purpose |
    | --- | --- |
    | Strictly necessary | These cookies are necessary for the website to function and cannot be switched off in our systems. They are usually only set in response to actions made by you.  <br>  <br>Strictly necessary cookies provide you with functionalities such as:<br><br>* Having the ability to log in<br>* Ensuring security<br>* Keeping your sessions alive<br>* Maintaining your checkout cart<br>* Traffic load balancing |
    | Functional | Functional cookies are not strictly necessary and can be disabled at any time. Their role is to provide the visitor with a better experience based on their preferences. |
    | Performance | Performance cookies are also optional cookies, and they are used to help us understand if the website is working as expected. We also use such cookies to analyze and measure traffic, including load times, counting the number of visitors accessing our website and other analytics that help us determine how to improve our products and services. |
    | Targeting | ChargePoint, ChargePoint partners or ChargePoint vendors may set cookies that measure and collect data about visitors’ interaction with our website in order to provide advertising services.  <br>  <br>Also, targeting cookies may be used for social media purposes to enable features such as content sharing from our website to different social media platforms. Targeting cookies are optional and can also be disabled at any time. |
    
3. **How we use information collected**  

    ChargePoint may use the information we collect from or about you for a range of business or commercial purposes.
    
    1. ChargePoint may use your account registration and charging app data to:
        * Process your application to create an account with ChargePoint
        * Provide our Service to you or your company (This includes providing information, products and services you request from us that enable you to access our charging network.)
        * Enable you to access external charging stations outside of the ChargePoint network (roaming)
        * Analyze usage patterns to improve our products and services
        * Process payment or reimbursement of fees (e.g., if you are the beneficiary of a charging arrangement with a provider)
        * Notify you of changes to our website or Service
    2. ChargePoint uses your ChargePoint station data to install a charging station at your premises, including making the install appointment and providing follow-up service.
    3. ChargePoint uses your Charging network data to manage and administer your account, including to distinguish between multiple vehicles or users under a single account and to analyze information about your charging sessions (e.g., duration, energy consumption, station owner and station data).
    4. ChargePoint uses your customer support data to:
        * Process your support cases in accordance with our contractual obligations
        * Continuously improve the quality of our support services and products through manual or automated means of analyzing the customer and support agent interaction and overall call sentiment
    5. ChargePoint uses your account registration data, business relationship data, charging network data and telematics data to:
        * Manage and respond to any inquiries, correspondence, concerns or complaints you have sent to us
        * Otherwise communicate with you as a customer or user regarding the use of our website or Service, including for sales and marketing purposes
    6. ChargePoint uses your location data to provide you with location-based features such as identifying the closest chargers relative to your position as well as to improve the positioning of our chargers on the map.
    7. ChargePoint uses your social media data to:
        * Enable you to communicate with other users (e.g., providing other users and site hosts information through driver tips)
        * Improve visibility of ChargePoint products through public tips provided by drivers
    8. ChargePoint uses your communication data to provide the ChargePoint Service and, to the extent we are obligated, to retain communication with you under the applicable laws (including tax, financial or other governmental regulations).
    9. ChargePoint uses account registration data to:
        * Notify you per SMS (e.g., for sending you a verification code, providing charging session receipts, messages related to the Waitlist feature, vehicle charging status, etc.)
        * Provide you with e-books and other information or services
    10. ChargePoint uses application and website data to:
        * Assist with customer service requests and accessibility
        * Keep our website and app secure and operational
        * Provide you with all services offered on our website and in the app
        * Track static and company IP addresses on the website for potential customer identification
    11. ChargePoint uses your account registration data, connections data, telematics data, ChargePoint station data, charging network data, and fraud and safety protection data to:
        * Safeguard the security of our systems and Service
        * Analyze and compile information on Service use patterns
        * Perform billing (including settling roaming charges) and customer support processes
        * Improve services and other elements of our business
        * Provide value-added services, promotions and pricing
    12. ChargePoint uses camera footage data to protect the persons and property at ChargePoint charging stations, offices, warehouses and high- and low-voltage labs.
    13. ChargePoint may use your account registration data and charging network data to provide you with advertising and marketing-related information about our products, services, sweepstakes, newsletters, events, promotions or information from our third-party partners that may interest you (only based on your consent where required by applicable law).
    14. ChargePoint may combine any of the information that we collect from you with other information, including information that we obtain from third parties or information derived from any other products or services we provide for general purpose uses, as permissible under this policy.  
          
        We may also aggregate or de-identify information collected through our Services and process such information as permitted by applicable law.
4. **When we disclose your information**  

    We may disclose any of the above categories of your information to third-party entities as follows:
    
    * Cooperation partners — for example, when we offer services together with a third party
    * IT and other service providers
    * Call centers — for example, when providing customer support
    * Charge point operators — for example, when we provide invoicing and billing services to charge point operators
    * Marketing service providers — for example, when we use third parties for marketing campaigns
    * Consultancies — for example, when we employ consultants to conduct market studies
    * Collection agencies and law firms — for example, when collecting unpaid invoices
    * File and data storage disposal services — for example, if we ask third parties to delete files or data
    * Cookie providers — in the app or on the website
    * Other vendors that perform services on our behalf
    * Our affiliates
    
    In addition, we provide personal data to third parties such as government or regulatory authorities when we have a legal obligation to do so. We may also disclose certain information if we believe in good faith that doing so is necessary or appropriate to protect or defend ChargePoint or other parties, including to defend or enforce this Policy, our Terms of Use or any other contractual arrangement or to protect the rights, property or personal safety of ChargePoint, our agents and affiliates, our employees, users or the public.
    
    We may disclose certain information if we believe in good faith that doing so is necessary or appropriate to comply with any law enforcement, legal or regulatory process, such as to respond to a warrant, subpoena, court order, or other applicable laws and regulations.
    
    We may also disclose or make available some of your information with advertising and analytics partners to serve advertisements on our behalf across the internet and to provide analytics services. These entities may use cookies and tracking technologies to allow us to, among other things, track and analyze data, determine the popularity of certain content, deliver advertising and content targeted to your interests and better understand your online activity.
    
    We may disclose certain information, in connection with or during negotiations or closing of any merger, sale of company assets, financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business, to another company.
    
    Except as stated above, we will not disclose your personal data to any third parties for any other purposes unless we have your consent or we otherwise have the legal basis or obligation to do so in an individual case.
    
    With respect to our disclosure of information to service providers and third-party network providers, such parties may have limited access to certain features and data from the ChargePoint network to be able to provide the required services (such as billing and pricing). If you are a beneficiary of a charging arrangement with a provider, for example, when your employer or a leasing company has agreed to cover the cost of your charging session, the provider will have access to your session and, in some cases, to certain data within your account.
    
    With regard to the processing of such data, ChargePoint and the provider are either individual (sole) controllers or joint controllers, depending on the contractual agreement. Please refer to the provider’s privacy policy to understand how they process, collect, use and disclose your data. If you would like a summary of the commitments between the parties where ChargePoint is a joint controller, please use the contact information provided in Section 11.
    
    No mobile information will be shared with third parties/affiliates for marketing/promotional purposes. All other categories exclude text messaging originator opt-in data and consent; this information will not be shared with any third parties
    
5. **Security measures**  

    ChargePoint has implemented administrative, physical and technical security measures to protect your information under our control.
    
    While ChargePoint takes precautions against possible security breaches of its website and Service, no website or internet transmission is completely secure, and we cannot guarantee that unauthorized access, hacking, data loss or other breaches will never occur. We are unable to guarantee the security of your information while it is being transmitted to our website or stored in our systems, and any transmission is at your own risk.
    
    You should take steps to keep your information safe (including your password) and log out of your account after use. Where we have provided or you have chosen a password that enables you to access certain parts of our website or an RFID card that provides access to charging stations, you are responsible for keeping your password and RFID card confidential. You must not share these with anyone or store them in a way that may allow a third party to access them. If that happens, you should report it immediately to the contact provided in Section 11. ChargePoint cannot be held and is not responsible for your failure to keep your password or RFID card secure.
    
    You should update your password periodically to help reduce the risk of unauthorized access to your account with us. When you do, you should strengthen your password with the combination of uppercase and lowercase letters, numbers, punctuation and other symbols.
    
6. **Retention, deletion and storage**  

    We generally retain information for as long as it may be relevant to the purposes above and in compliance with applicable law. To dispose of any personal data, we may anonymize it, delete it or take other appropriate steps. Information may persist in copies made for backup and business continuity purposes for an additional period of time.
    
7. **Links to third-party websites and services**  

    This website may contain links to third-party sites. Access to any other websites linked from our website is at the user’s own risk, and ChargePoint is not responsible for the accuracy or reliability of any information, data, opinions, advice or statements made on those websites. ChargePoint provides these links merely as a convenience, and the inclusion of such links does not imply any kind of endorsement. If you provide any third party with your information, we recommend that you review their privacy policies as ChargePoint does not control how they collect, process and transfer your information.
    
8. **Your choices**  
      
    * **Account information.** You may modify some of your account information by accessing your account or contacting Customer Service (please see Section 11, Contact us).
    * **Marketing communications.** You may unsubscribe from our marketing communications by following the directions in those communications. Please note that we may still send you certain communications relating to your use of our Service (e.g., service announcements, notices about new features or information on the Service, administrative messages, and communications about your account).
9. **Children’s privacy**  

    The website and Service are intended for persons licensed to drive. In the United States, this typically means individuals over age 16 and, in Europe, age 17. ChargePoint does not knowingly collect any information from anyone under 16. If you are under 16 or 17, we request that you do not submit information to us. If we become aware that we have inadvertently collected “personal information” (as defined by the United States Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act) from children under the age of 13 without parental consent, we will take reasonable steps to delete it as soon as possible as required by applicable law.
    
10. **Changes to our privacy policy**  

    We may change this Policy to reflect changes in the law, our information practices or the features of the Service. At the top of our Policy, we will indicate the date of the most recent update. If we make a material change to the Policy, you will be provided with appropriate notice in accordance with legal requirements, which may be by email. By continuing to use the Service, you are confirming that you have read and understood the latest version of this Policy.
    
11. **Contact us**
    * North America:
        * Email: [privacy@chargepoint.com](mailto:privacy@chargepoint.com)
        * Phone (24/7): +1-888-758-4389
        * Web form: [https://na.chargepoint.com/guest/chargepoint\_help](https://na.chargepoint.com/guest/chargepoint_help)
        * Snail mail: ChargePoint, Attn: Legal Department, 254 E. Hacienda Avenue, Campbell, CA 95008-6901
    * European Economic Area and the United Kingdom:
        * Email: [privacy.eu@chargepoint.com](mailto:privacy.eu@chargepoint.com)
        * Snail mail: ChargePoint, Attn: Customer Service, ChargePoint Network (Netherlands) B.V., Hoogoorddreef 56E, 1101BE Amsterdam, Netherlands
12. **Regional privacy rights**
    1. Nevada residents
        
        Nevada consumers may opt out of the sale of “personally identifiable information” (as that term is defined by NRS 603A.040) for monetary consideration. We do not engage in such activity; however, if you are a Nevada resident who has purchased or leased goods or services from us, you may submit a request to opt out of any potential future sales under Nevada law by emailing [privacy@chargepoint.com](mailto:privacy@chargepoint.com). Please note we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity and the authenticity of the request. Once verified, we will maintain your request in the event our practices change.
        
    2. Residents of the European Economic Area, Switzerland and United Kingdom (“Europe”)
        1. Our legal basis for processing your personal data
            
            When you visit our website from Europe, indicate you are a European resident, when using our services in Europe or when you visit our European offices, the controller of any personal information processed is ChargePoint Network (Netherlands) B.V. (see contact in Section 11).
            
            ChargePoint uses the following legal basis for processing your personal information:
            
            * **Contractual commitments (Art. 6 (1) (b) GDPR).** We may use, share or disclose information to honor our contractual commitments to you. For example, we may process personal data to perform our agreement with you under the ChargePoint Driver Terms of Service, and if applicable, under an agreement between ChargePoint and a provider that governs the terms of the ChargePoint network services.
            * **Your consent (Art. 6 (1) a) GDPR).** Where required by law, and in some other cases as described above, we use, share or disclose information with your consent. You may withdraw your consent at any time by emailing privacy.eu@chargepoint.com.
            * **Legitimate interests (Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR).** In some cases, we use, share or disclose information on the ground that it furthers our legitimate business interests in ways that are not overridden by the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of the affected individuals, such as customer service, certain promotional activities, analyzing and improving our business, providing security for our Services, preventing fraud and managing legal issues.
            * **Legal compliance (Art. 6 (1) (c) GDPR).** We need to use, share and disclose information in certain ways to comply with our legal obligations. This includes processing personal data subject to tax, financial or other governmental regulations.
            
            We will not process any of your personal data without having a legal basis for doing so.
            
            You have no statutory or contractual obligation to provide us with any personal data. However, depending on the activity, some of the information we may ask you to provide is identified as mandatory (because we need it in order to provide the requested Service). If you do not provide the mandatory data with respect to a particular Service, you will not be able to use that Service.
            
        2. Transfer of personal data to countries outside the European Union or without an adequate level of data protection as determined by the European Commission
            
            ChargePoint is a global company that operates its website and Service through servers located in several countries. If you select a country in Europe as your country of residence, your personal data is mainly hosted on servers within the European Union.
            
            We may have to grant access to your personal data, such as account registration and charging network data, to ChargePoint affiliates in the United States and India (e.g., to provide you with support when receiving Services or to allow analysis of the data to develop and improve our products and services). Those purposes include usage patterns of the ChargePoint charging station network that help inform product development, safety features, sales strategy, support and maintenance.
            
            Further, these ChargePoint entities may need to access information for billing and accounting purposes. Transfers to these ChargePoint entities are based on the appropriate standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission. You may request further information about our transfer safeguards by sending an email to [privacy.eu@chargepoint.com](mailto:privacy.eu@chargepoint.com).
            
        3. Rights of European residents
            
            European privacy laws grant you the following rights as a data subject:
            
            * **Right of access.** You have the right to confirm whether or not your personal data is being processed, and if yes, request access to that personal data and certain other information.
            * **Right to rectification.** You have the right to request the correction of your personal data. Taking into account the purposes of the processing, you have the right to have incomplete personal data completed.
            * **Right to deletion.** You have the right to request the deletion of your personal data or data concerning you without undue delay.
            * **Right to restriction of processing.** You have the right to request the restriction of processing.
            * **Right to data portability.** You have the right to request your personal data, which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, and you may transmit this data to another controller. You also have the right to request the personal data to be transmitted directly from us to another controller, where technically feasible.
            * **Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.** Without prejudice to any other administrative or judicial remedy, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the country of your habitual residence, place of work or place of the alleged infringement, if you consider that the processing of personal data relating to you infringes European privacy laws. For the Netherlands, the supervisory authority is the Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens. For the United Kingdom, the regulator is the Information Commissioner’s Office. In addition to the rights mentioned above, you also have the right to object to certain processing and the right to withdraw your consent, where processing is based on such.
            * **Right to object.** You have the right to object at any time, on grounds relating to your particular situation, to the processing of your personal data, based on legitimate interests or for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the controller. In such case, we shall no longer process the personal data unless we demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing, which override your interests, rights and freedoms or where the processing is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims. Where personal data is processed for direct marketing purposes, you shall have the right to object at any time to processing of your personal data for such purposes, which includes profiling to the extent that it is related to such direct marketing. If you would like to object to any processing of your personal data, please send us a message in writing to ChargePoint at the address detailed above or email us at privacy.eu@chargepoint.com.
            * **Right to withdraw consent.** Where the processing is based on your informed consent, you have the right to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal. Therefore, you may send us a message in writing to ChargePoint at the address detailed above or via email at privacy.eu@chargepoint.com.
        4. Retention of your personal data
            
            As also described above in Section 6, we generally retain information for as long as it may be relevant to the purposes above and in compliance with applicable law. To dispose of any personal data, we may anonymize it, delete it or take other appropriate steps. Information may persist in copies made for backup and business continuity purposes for an additional period of time.
            
            The following table summarizes our retention times for your personal data:
            
            | Data category | Data retention schedule |
            | --- | --- |
            | * Account registration data<br>* ChargePoint station data<br>* Customer support data<br>* Communication data<br>* Social media data | 3 years |
            | * Charging network data<br>* Invoices and other VAT records | 5-10 years, depending on the country in scope |
            | * Business relationship data | For the duration of the contract |
            | * Telematics data | For the duration of the contract |
            | * App and website data<br>* Location data<br>* Survey data | 1 year |
            | * Camera footage | * 72 hours for office entrances and exits<br>* Up to 30 days for high-risk areas, including factories, high and low-voltage labs and warehouses |
            
    3. Supplemental privacy notice for California residents
        
        The California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) requires us to disclose information regarding the categories of personal information and sensitive personal information that we have collected about California consumers, the categories of sources from which the information was collected, the business or commercial purposes (as those terms are defined by applicable law) for which the information was collected, and the categories of parties to whom we disclose personal information.
        
        Throughout this Policy, we describe the specific pieces of personal information and sensitive personal information we collect, the sources of that information and when we disclose it. Under the CCPA, we also have to provide you with the “categories” of personal information and sensitive personal information we collect and disclose for “business or commercial purposes” (as those terms are defined by applicable law). The categories of personal information are identifiers (such as name, address and email address), commercial information (such as transaction data), financial data (such as credit card and other financial account information), internet or other network or device activity (such as IP address), professional or employment-related information (such as your current employer), geolocation information, inference data about you, physical characteristics or description (such as when you voluntarily submit a photo), audio and visual information (such as when you call into customer service or visit our offices) and other information that identifies or can be reasonably associated with you. The categories of sensitive personal information are account log-in and password or other credentials allowing access to your account and precise geolocation.
        
        ChargePoint and our service providers collect and disclose the above categories of personal information for the purposes described in our Policy. This includes the following business and commercial purposes (as those terms are defined in applicable law):
        
        * Provision of the Service (e.g., account servicing and maintenance, order processing and fulfillment, customer service, advertising and marketing, analytics, and communication about the Service)
        * Operations (e.g., to enable and troubleshoot our Service)
        * Audit of consumer interactions on our site (e.g., measuring ad impressions)
        * Security and integrity to the extent the use of the personal information is reasonably necessary and proportionate for these purposes
        * Bug detection, error reporting and activities to maintain the quality or safety of our Service
        * Short-term, transient use, such as customizing content that we or our service providers display on the Service
        * Improvement of our existing Service and development of new services (e.g., by conducting research to develop new products or features or analyzing and measuring our customer support interactions)
        * Activities that advance our commercial or economic interests, such as third-party advertising and communications with you about relevant offers from third-party partners
        * Other purposes about which we will notify you
        
        We collect the categories of personal information identified above directly from you, through your use of the Service, from our affiliates and from third parties such as site hosts, other users and social networks.
        
        We describe our information-sharing practices in the Policy above. In the previous 12 months, we may have disclosed certain categories of personal information with unaffiliated parties (as defined by the CCPA) for the business purposes described above. For example, we may disclose your information with providers when you connect with a ChargePoint station operated by that provider, or site host. You may also intentionally direct us to disclose your information with utility companies or their vendors. The information we disclose with providers and utility companies may include account registration data (identifiers) and charging network data (commercial information).
        
        ### Rights of California consumers
        
        If you are a California resident, you may have certain rights. California law may permit you to request that we:
        
        * Provide you the categories of personal information we have collected or disclosed about you; the categories of sources of such information; the business or commercial purpose for collecting, selling or sharing your personal information; the categories of third parties to whom we disclose, sell or share personal information; and the categories of personal information we sell or share
        * Provide access to or a copy of certain information we hold about you
        * Delete certain information we have about you
        * Correct inaccurate personal information that we maintain about you
        
        You may have the right to receive information about the financial incentives that we offer to you, if any. You also have the right to not be discriminated against (as provided for in applicable law) for exercising certain of your rights. Certain information may be exempt from such requests under applicable law. We need certain types of information so that we can provide the Service to you. If you ask us to delete it, you may no longer be able to access or use the Service.
        
        If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please submit a request through one of our available channels:
        
        * Email: [privacy@chargepoint.com](mailto:privacy@chargepoint.com)li>
        * Webform: [https://na.chargepoint.com/guest/chargepoint\_help](https://na.chargepoint.com/guest/chargepoint_help), or
        * Phone (24/7): +1-888-758-4389
        
        You will be required to verify your identity before we fulfill your request. To do so, you will need to provide the information identified in the webform or as otherwise directed by us. You can also designate an authorized agent to make a request on your behalf. To do so, you must provide us with written authorization or a power of attorney, signed by you, for the agent to act on your behalf. You will still need to verify your identity directly with us.
        
        The CCPA requires businesses that sell personal information, as the term “sell” is defined under the CCPA, to provide an opt-out from such sales. Some people have taken the position that when a website uses third-party cookies or similar technology for its own analytics or advertising purposes, the website is engaged in a “sale” under the CCPA if the third parties have some ability to use, disclose or retain the data to improve their service or to take steps beyond the most narrowly drawn bounds of merely providing their service to the website or app. Some take this position even when the website pays the third party (not vice versa) and, in most cases, merely provides the third party with an opportunity to collect data directly, instead of providing personal information to the third party. These analytics and advertising services technologies may access identifiers (such as IP addresses), internet or other electronic network activity information (such as information regarding an individual’s browsing interactions on a ChargePoint website) and commercial information (such as the fact that a browser visited a page directed to people who are considering an electric vehicle) to those sorts of companies. While ChargePoint does not believe these are “sales” as that term is defined under the CCPA, you can opt out of this activity by changing your “privacy choices” on our website (when accessing the ChargePoint [website](https://www.chargepoint.com/), you will be presented with a privacy preference center which will enable your choices).
        
        The CCPA also requires businesses that share personal information to provide an opt-out from such sharing. Under the CCPA, sharing is defined as the targeting of advertising to a consumer based on that consumer’s personal information obtained from the consumer’s activity across websites. We share information for these purposes to provide more relevant and tailored advertising to you regarding our Services. As part of this advertising, we may share identifiers (such as IP addresses and email addresses), internet or other electronic network activity information (such as information regarding an individual’s browsing interactions on a ChargePoint website), and commercial information (such as the fact that a browser visited a page directed to people who are considering an electric vehicle) with advertising platforms and advertising networks. To opt out of such sharing, please change your “privacy choices” online, on our website (when accessing the ChargePoint [website](https://www.chargepoint.com/), you will be presented with a privacy preference center which will enable your choices).
        
        Please note that we also respond to and abide by opt-out preference signals sent through the Global Privacy Control. Any opt-out preferences you have indicated through these methods will only apply to the specific device or browser on which you made them. For more information on how to use the Global Privacy Control, please visit www.globalprivacycontrol.org.
        
        We do not knowingly sell or share the personal information of children under 16.
        
        The CCPA also allows you to limit the use or disclosure of your sensitive personal information (as defined in the CCPA) if your sensitive personal information is used for certain purposes. Please note that we do not use or disclose sensitive personal information other than for purposes for which you cannot opt out under the CCPA.
        
        The retention schedule of your personal information is further detailed above, in Section 6, Retention, deletion and storage.
        
        **California Do Not Track setting.** We do not respond to browser-initiated Do Not Track signals, as the internet industry is currently still working on Do Not Track standards, implementations and solutions. Please note that Do Not Track is a different privacy mechanism than the Global Privacy Control browser choice referenced above.
        
    4. Supplemental privacy notice for other US states
        
        Depending on where you live, you may have certain rights. Where applicable, the state law may permit you to request that we:
        
        * Confirm whether or not we are processing your personal information and provide you with access to such personal information
        * Correct inaccuracies in your personal information, taking into account the nature of the personal information and the purposes of the processing of the personal information
        * Delete your personal information
        * Provide you a copy of personal information that you previously provided to us in a portable and, to the extent technically feasible, readily usable format that allows you to transmit the data to another business, where our processing is carried out by automated means
        * Opt you out of the processing of the personal information for purposes of targeted advertising, the sale of personal information or profiling in furtherance of decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects concerning you
        
        Certain information may be exempt from such requests under applicable law. We need certain types of information so we can provide the Service to you. If you ask us to delete it, you may no longer be able to access or use the Service.
        
        If would like to exercise any of these rights, please submit a request at [privacy@chargepoint.com](mailto:privacy@chargepoint.com) or visit [https://na.chargepoint.com/guest/chargepoint\_help](https://na.chargepoint.com/guest/chargepoint_help). You will be required to verify your identity before we fulfill your request. To do so, you will need to provide the information identified in the webform or as otherwise directed by us.
        
        ChargePoint may use your personal information to send you targeted advertising (as that term is defined in certain state privacy laws). To opt out of targeted advertising, please change your privacy choices online (when accessing the ChargePoint [website](https://www.chargepoint.com/), you will be presented with a privacy preference center which will enable your preferences).
        
        Depending on where you live, if we deny your request to exercise any of the rights above, you may have the right to appeal that denial by contacting us at [privacy@chargepoint.com](mailto:privacy@chargepoint.com) with the subject “Data privacy request appeal” and providing us with information about why you are appealing the decision.
        
    5. Supplemental Privacy Notice for Canada
        
        If you are a Canadian resident or if your personal data is processed by ChargePoint’s Canadian Legal Entity, you have the right to access your personal information. To exercise that right, please submit a request at [privacy@chargepoint.com](mailto:privacy@chargepoint.com) or visit [https://na.chargepoint.com/guest/chargepoint\_help](https://na.chargepoint.com/guest/chargepoint_help). You will be required to verify your identity before we fulfill your request. To do so, you will need to provide the information identified in the webform or as otherwise directed by us. Certain information may be exempt from such requests under applicable law.
        
        ChargePoint is a global company that operates its website and Service through servers located in several countries. We may grant access to your personal data (such as account registration and charging network data) to ChargePoint affiliates in the United States and India, where that data may be accessible to law enforcement and national security authorities under certain circumstances.
        
    6. Supplemental Privacy Notice for Mexico
        
        This Supplemental Privacy Notice supplements the information in our Privacy Policy, and except as provided herein, applies solely to data subjects in Mexico. It applies to personal information we collect on or through the Service and through other means (such as information collected offline, in person, and over the telephone).
        
        For individuals in Mexico, Charge Point, Inc., with address at 240 East Hacienda Ave, Campbell, California 95008 and ChargePoint Mexico, S. de R.L. de C.V., with address at Avenida de las Américas No. 1536, Piso 5 B-2, Col. Country Club, 44610 Guadalajara, Jalisco shall be considered as the data controllers for the processing of personal data.
        
        Access, Rectification, Cancellation and Opposition (“ARCO”) Rights
        
        Subject to certain exceptions detailed in the Mexican law, you have the right to: (i) request access to your Mexican information; (ii) request deletion of the Mexican information we collected from you; (iii) request correction of inaccurate Mexican information; and (iv) oppose to particular processing activities, unless those are necessary for the maintenance of the legal relationship with us. We will not discriminate against you for exercising such rights. You also have the right to revoke any consent previously granted.
        
        To request such rights, or for any questions, please email [privacy@chargepoint.com](mailto:support@chargepoint.com) and in the subject line of your email, please indicate “Mexico Privacy Rights Request ARCO RIGHTS: (Insert Your Name)”). In addition, please confirm: (i) name of the data subject and email address or means to communicate the respective response; (ii) documents proving your identity, or the identity of legal representative; (iii) clear and precise description of the personal data in respect of which you seek to exercise any of your ARCO Rights; and (iv) documents or information that facilitates the location of the respective personal data.
        
        To the extent that you elect to designate an authorized agent to make a request on your behalf, they must provide appropriate documentation including written signed permission from you, proof of your identity, and verification of their identity; or a valid, designated power of attorney as defined under the Mexican Civil Code.
